In this American English pronunciation video,
在这段美式英语发音视频中，
we're going to learn how to pronounce the AY as in SAY diphthong.
我们将学习如何发音AY，如同SAY中的双元音。
Diphthongs are a combination of two sounds,
双元音是两个音的组合，
so they have a starting position and an ending position.
所以它们有一个起始位置和一个结束位置。
In the first position,
在第一个位置，
the jaw drops and the tongue tip touches the back of the bottom front teeth.
下巴下垂，舌尖触碰下前牙的后面。
The top of the tongue pushes forward and lifts a bit.
舌头的顶部向前推并稍微抬起。
The second sound is the IH as in SIT vowel.
第二个音是IH，如同SIT中的元音。
To transition into this position,
为了过渡到这个位置，
your jaw will lift as the top,
你的下巴会抬起，
front part of the tongue arches towards the roof of the mouth.
舌头的前上部向口腔顶部拱起。
Let's look at a word with this sound,
让我们看看一个包含这个音的单词，
pay.
pay。
The jaw drops and you can see a lot of tongue as the front and middle push up and forward.
下巴下垂，你可以看到很多舌头，因为前部和中部向上和向前推。
As the top, front part of the tongue arches up towards the roof of the mouth,
当舌头的前上部向口腔顶部拱起时，
the jaw comes up.
下巴抬起。
Lips are relaxed for this diphthong.
这个双元音的嘴唇是放松的。
AY, pay.
AY，pay。
In a stressed syllable like pay,
在像pay这样的重读音节中，
the AY diphthong curves up, then down.
AY双元音先上升，然后下降。
Pay,
Pay，
AY.
AY。
In an unstressed syllable,
在非重读音节中，
it's lower and flatter in pitch,
音调更低更平，
as well as quicker and quieter.
而且更快更轻。
AY, AY.
AY，AY。
The diphthong is unstressed in the word driveway,
在单词driveway中，双元音是非重读的，
AY.
AY。
Let's take a look at this word.
让我们看看这个单词。
Just as before,
就像之前一样，
the jaw drops and you can see a lot of tongue as the front and middle push up and forward.
下巴下垂，你可以看到很多舌头，因为前部和中部向上和向前推。
Then the top, front part of the tongue arches up towards the roof of the mouth,
然后舌头的前上部向口腔顶部拱起，
and the jaw comes up.
下巴抬起。
Jaw drop may be a little less when this diphthong is in an unstressed syllable,
当这个双元音在非重读音节中时，下巴的下垂可能会少一些，
as we tend to simplify mouth movements in unstressed syllables,
因为我们倾向于在非重读音节中简化口腔动作，
which are shorter.
这些音节更短。
The AY diphthong, stressed.
AY双元音，重读。
Pay,
Pay，
AY.
AY。
Unstressed.
非重读。
Driveway.
Driveway。
AY.
AY。
AY,
AY，
AY.
AY。
AY,
AY，
AY.
AY。
Example words.
例词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Okay.
Okay。
AY.
AY。
Okay.
Okay。
Play.
Play。
AY.
AY。
Play.
Play。
Operate.
Operate。
AY.
AY。
Operate.
Operate。
Gain.
Gain。
AY.
AY。
Gain.
Gain。
Separate.
Separate。
AY.
AY。
Separate.
Separate。
AY.
AY。
Pain.
Pain。